Contact

+4915752577230 (Mobile) robert.focke@member.fsf.org

www.linkedin.com/in/robertfocke (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Linux

SQL

Python

Languages

Afrikaans (Native or Bilingual)
English (Native or Bilingual)
German (Professional Working)

Honors-Awards

3rd Place, Mobile Application Development Challenge Information Technology Subject Prize

Robert Focke

Junior Software Developer at Norwegian Refugee Council Berlin, Berlin, Germany

Summary

I am a young professional in the computer science and linguistics field, interested in machine learning, big data and computational linguistics.

I have good knowledge of general software development including full-stack web development and modern devops, with experience working with both corporate and startup clients.

Experience

Norwegian Refugee Council Junior Software Developer April 2019 - Present

Berlin Area, Germany

Software development as part of the NRC D-Team which is responsible for architecting and building an ecosystem of technological solutions to manage data flow from collection to complex analysis across NRC's operations globally.

Clickwash Co-Founder, Chief Architect October 2018 - Present

Berlin Area, Germany

Involved in the early development of the ClickWash web application and project in general. ClickWash brings distributed economic principles to the car washing space.

Development of the ClickWash web application using the following stack:

- Nginx (Reverse Proxy, SSL)
- SupervisorD (Process Management)
- Gunicorn (Application Server)
- HTML/Jinja/CSS/JS (Frontend)
- Python 3 (Backend)
- MongoDB (Storage)

The ClickWash web application also makes use OSM services, predominantly OSRM.

Fridaysuite Pty Ltd.
Co-Founder, Technical Adviser
October 2015 - Present
Pretoria Area, South Africa

System design and coordination of development of the Fridaysuite web application. Development of software predominantly written in Python (flask) and JavaScript. Automation of deployment to Amazon Web Services using the Boto3 python SDK. Administration of the Fridaysuite system using nginx, gunicorn, supervisord and laminar.

Technical Advisor, leading transition to more mature version of the architecture.

Norwegian Refugee Council Freelance Software Developer March 2019 - April 2019 (2 months) Johannesburg Area, South Africa

Remote work involving automation and QA testing as part of the NRC D-Team. Docker, Nginx, BASH. Mainly focused on Apache NiFi and SalesForce, but also making use of Nagios for monitoring.

Self-employed Software Consultant October 2018 - April 2019 (7 months) Johannesburg Area, South Africa

Full stack web development
Custom software development
Machine learning applications

SAP

1 year 9 months

Knowledge Manager (Working Student) January 2018 - September 2018 (9 months) Berlin Area, Germany

Working student position.

Technical enablement, information development and content creation within the topics of Machine Learning, Cloud Computing and Digital Transformation.

Product documentation working closely with development, UX design, agile product management, business development and customers.

Product testing, QA relating to the SAP Leonardo Machine Learning platform.

Software Engineer (Working Student) January 2017 - December 2017 (1 year) Berlin Area, Germany

Working as a working student in the Berlin office of the SAP Innovation Centre Network. Working as part of the team developing the SAP Leonardo ML Platform. Python, Java, C++ and Groovy development in an agile environment.

Worked as part of the Google-SAP partnership, creating a proxy of Google's speech recognition service. Also worked with ABBYY OCR Engine, Docker, CloudFoundry, Flask, Jenkins.

HomeToGo System Administrator (Working Student) February 2016 - July 2016 (6 months) Berlin Area, Germany

Manage network in the Berlin Office (Juniper Switches, Mikrotik Routers, Cisco APs). Resolving IT related problems. Stock-taking of IT related assets. Raspberry Pis for PR and Google Analytics. Automation using shell scripting (Bash),

Education

Open Source Society University
Bachelor's degree, Computer Science · (2018 - 2020)

Technische Universität Berlin
Coursework, Computer Engineering (2015 - 2018)

Pretoria Boys High School High School · (2010 - 2014)